制作: 星际迷航中国字幕组 (https://www.startrekchina.org)
翻译: 在爬墙的胡子 & 北窗高卧久息尘 & 铜绿 & 诺北 & Bruce & 凌塔
校对: narwhrl
时轴: narwhrl
特效: narwhrl
日期: 2025-07-27
《星际迷航: 新世界》前情提要
Previously on Strange New Worlds...
我现在要给你注射镇定剂了
I'm gonna give you a sedative now.
等你醒来 戈恩感染的问题就治好了
And when you wake up, you will be Gorn-free.
我还在这里
I'm still here.
你能撑住的
You are going to make it.
我可是艾丽卡·奥特加斯 无敌舵手
I'm Erica Ortegas. I fly the ship.
伍中恋爱可能会导致一些复杂的问题
Fraternization can lead to complications.
就像我一直在告诉你的那样 我只是需要点个人时间
Like I've been trying to tell you, I just need some personal time.
远离我的时间
Away from me.
我正在考虑申请考古医学研究员的职位
About that fellowship, the archaeological medicine?
我得开始找人替补你了 是不是
I'm going to have to replace you, aren't I?
失去你的念头
The thought of losing you,
深深困扰着我
it affected me deeply.
但我还是要离开三个月
I am still going away for three months
去和罗杰·科尔比一起学习
to study with Roger Korby.
等我回来 再看看我们的状态吧
When I get back, let's just see where we are then.
科学官个人日志
Science officer's personal log,
星历2251.7
stardate 2251.7.
在一号星站驻扎三个月后
After a three-month billet at Starbase One,
我们与戈恩人交战造成的损伤
the battle scars of our encounter 科尔比
已经被全数修复
with the Gorn are all but erased,
这给我留下了很多时间去思考
which has left me with a great deal of time to think.
联邦日百年庆典
The Federation Day Centennial--
庆祝星际联邦成立
the 100th anniversary of the founding of
一百周年的日子
the United Federation of Planets--
还有三天就到了
is just three days away.
派克舰长认为 为联邦日组织一场庆典晚会
Captain Pike believes that hosting a ceremonial gala for Federation Day
可以提振船员的士气
will improve morale among the crew.
每一位船员的士气
All of the crew.
查普尔护士结束外出 即将返舰
Nurse Chapel is returning from her time away.
自从她离开去参加项目后 我们就再未联系过
We have not spoken since she left for her fellowship.
因此 我也有一个更加私人的理由
As such, I have a more personal reason to prepare
来准备即将到来的庆典
for the upcoming celebrations.
放松你的肩膀
Loosen up your shoulders.
我的肩膀位置已经过精确测量
My shoulder placement has been measured precisely.
又没让你去精确测量肩膀位置
You're not supposed to measure them.
你该让它们顺其自然
You're supposed to let them flow.
就像这样
Like this.
我不明白
I am confused.
我不是已经按照你要求的参数
Am I not already performing the movements to the
表演这些动作了吗
parameters you specified?
你是 你只是太僵硬了
Yes. You're just stiff.
就算是你 也僵得过分了
Even for you.
五 六 七 走
Five, six, seven, and...
请不要误会我的意思
Please do not take this the wrong way,
你在这项活动上的天赋令人惊讶
but your aptitude for this activity is surprising,
而且恕我直言
and if I may say so,
我认为这种愿意尝试新事物的态度非常适合你
this openness to new life experiences suits you.
有那么一段时间
There was a time
我最大的愿望就是成为一位芭蕾舞的首席演员
when I wanted nothing more than to be a prima ballerina.
我猜测是戈恩人改变了你的想法
I assume the Gorn changed that?
没错 我这辈子都在
That's just it. I've spent my whole life
等着他们卷土重来
waiting for them to come back.
就像是我童年床底下的怪物
My own personal nightmare under the bed.
然后他们真的回来了
And here's the thing-- they came back
而我打败了他们 就这样
and I beat them. Anyway...
但是呢
somehow
跟首席芭蕾舞演员比起来
the Gorn are less ravenous
戈恩人都算温顺的
than prima ballerinas.
也许这就是为什么瓦肯人原则上不跳舞
Perhaps that is why Vulcans, as a rule, do not dance.
看来就算是瓦肯人 也会为了特别的人而打破常规
It seems some of you will defy that rule for the right person.
在人类文化中 久别重逢之际进行隆重的浪漫表达
When humans reunite after a long absence, is it not tradition
难道不是传统吗
to make a grand romantic gesture?
史波克 我不想八卦
Spock, I-I don't want to pry,
但你和克莉丝汀不是决定
but I thought you and Christine had
暂时分开 给彼此一点个人空间吗
decided to give each other some space.
确实
Indeed.
自从她离开去参加项目后 我们就再未联系过
We have not spoken since she left for her fellowship.
不过大家都知道 距离最容易牵动人心
But we all know what absence does to the heart.
如果没了「心」将会是致命的
The absence of a heart would be quite fatal.
不 史波克 这只是比喻 我是说
No, Spock, it's an idiom, it's...
进取号呼叫史波克先生
Enterprise to Mr. Spock.
你要我提醒你 那好 注意了
You asked for a heads-up, so, heads up.
查普尔护士请求传送许可了
Transport clearance request from Nurse Chapel.
她来了 我先失陪了
Please excuse me. She is here.
挺帅啊 史波克先生
Looking good, Mr. Spock.
你怎么在这
Lieutenant?
职责需要
Just doing my job.
查普尔在访客名单上加了人
Chapel added someone to the visitors list.
有趣
Curious.
有点怪
That's funny.
刚刚某个瞬间
You know, for a wee moment there, I thought
我还以为我看到了一点异样
I saw a bit of strangeness.
什么样的异样
What sort of strangeness?
只是个船体外的传感器虚影
Oh, just a sensor ghost outside the hull.
但它现在不见了
But it's gone now.
没啥值得看的 长官
Nothing to see here, sir.
所有相关的扫描结果均处在正常范围内
All relevant scans appear to be within normal parameters.
斯考特中尉 传送两人上舰
Two to beam aboard, Lieutenant Scott.
史波克
Spock.
克莉丝汀
Christine.
这位是科尔比博士
Uh, this is Dr. Korby.
-你的研究项目指导? -嗯哼
- Your fellowship director? - Mm-hmm.
科尔比博士 向您问好
Greetings, Dr. Korby.
你好你好 叫我罗杰就行
How are you? Call me Roger.
我听说了不少关于你的事 史波克
I've, uh, heard a lot about you, Spock.
科尔比博士 我也读过许多您
Dr. Korby, I have read a considerable number
在考古医学领域上的论文
of your papers on archaeological medicine.
其实也没那么多
Oh, sure, there aren't that many.
一共有二百三十四篇 我说错了吗
There are 234. Is that not accurate?
没错 确实是这么多
It's actually exactly how many there are.
哇哦
Wow.
那是第一版的《萨塔凡图尔》吗
Is that a first edition of Saltavantur?
可以看看吗
May I?
这太不可思议了
This is incredible.
光是这个雕刻设计肯定就能追溯到
The engravings alone must date back to...
这是给克莉丝汀的礼物
It is a gift for Christine.
哇
Wow.
总之 欢迎登舰 科尔比博士
Well, welcome aboard, Dr. Korby.
需要为你安排住宿吗
Will you be needing quarters?
呃 不用了
Uh, no, no, I'm, um...
我有安排了
I'm taken care of.
他是来这里
He is here
和我一起参加百年庆典的
to attend the centennial celebration with me.
和你?
With you?
科尔比博士是我的约会对象
Dr. Korby is my date.
厉害
Okay.
八英尺高的鬣蜥都没能干掉我
你小子想打倒我 还远着呢
继续啊 老弟
Come on, baby boy.
是想吃我一记重拳吗
你接不住我的全力重击的
You can't handle the haymaker.
谁说的
Who even says that?
谁说的不重要 你努力还击就行了 我们继续吧
你真是个讨厌鬼
准备好吃拳头吧
别太得意 我可要打中了啊
Don't get cocky, I'll land one.
喂
Hey!
我早就告诉过你把摄像机关掉
I told you to turn that camera off.
我只是在做我的工作啊
I'm just doing my job.
是啊 你的工作
Yeah, your job
是拍摄星联百年庆典的纪录片
is a documentary on the centennial gala,
而不是拍摄我们训练
not this workout.
我是一名专业的电影制作人
I am a serious filmmaker.
艾丽卡 可算找到你了
Erica, ah, there you are.
和你说件难以置信的事
You are not going to believe this.
克莉丝汀带了个男朋友回家
Christine brought home a date.
查普尔?
Chapel?
我刚知道的时候和你一样震惊
I'm just as shocked as you are.
嘿
Hey.
嗨 我是
Hi. I'm, uh--
重拳出击
Haymaker!
好吧 这是谁
Okay, who's this?
这是我弟弟
That's my little brother.
他从来就接不住拳头
Never could take a punch.
嗨
Hi.
我是妮欧塔
I'm Nyota.
行了 就快好了
All right, almost done.
不急的 少尉
Take your time, Ensign.
百年庆典的准备工作那么多
With all the centennial preparations I have to do,
这已经是我最接近度假的待遇了
this is the closest thing to a vacation I'm gonna get.
这就是最后一管了
Well, this is the last one,
但是我可以再抽几管
but I can take a bunch more.
说真的 一个人能需要多少血啊
I mean, how much blood does a person really need?
护士学校没教这个吗
They didn't cover that in nursing school?
我上课时候睡着了
Oof, I fell asleep.
还很经常
Like, a lot.
我挺喜欢你的 少尉
I like you, Ensign.
可是呢 现在查普尔护士回来了
Well, now that Nurse Chapel is back,
我的临时任命期就结束了
my temporary assignment is done.
话别说的这么绝对
I wouldn't be so sure.
别这样看着我
Don't look at me.
去看你的直属上司去
Take it up with your direct supervisor.
你猜对了
Guilty as charged.
我已经向星际舰队医疗部提交了申请
I put in a request with Starfleet Medical
希望把你的调任期限转为永久
to make your transfer permanent.
等等 别骗我啊 别最后告诉我只是恶作剧
Wait, wait, please tell me this isn't a cruel joke.
我们这最喜欢玩这种恶作剧了
We are big on cruel jokes around here.
等你第一次参加舰长的晚宴就知道了
Just wait until your first formal Captain's Table.
不过这次确实是认真的
But in this case, no.
很显然 你上司不舍得让你离开
Apparently, he isn't ready to give you up.
诚实地说 我们都不舍得看你离开 少尉
Frankly, none of us are, Ensign.
谢谢
Thank you.
能有你在 巴特尔舰长真是幸运
Captain Batel is lucky to have you.
玛丽恢复得怎么样了
How's Marie doing?
扫描结果显示
Her scans show that
戈恩胚胎残余物质已经被她的身体完全吸收了
the Gorn embryos have been fully reabsorbed.
是你的血让她的身体足够强韧
It was your blood that kept her body
才顺利撑过了代谢吸收的过程
strong enough to survive the metabolization process.
我们只是处理了一些轻微的后遗症罢了
All we're doing now is managing some minor aftereffects.
我都习惯了她的存在了
I've gotten used to having her on board.
她要是走了我还真有点舍不得
I'll be sorry to see her go.
要是如此 难过的肯定不止你一个
I imagine you won't be the only one.
说真的
I have literally
有些勋章我都不知道是为什么颁的
no idea what some of these medals are for.
而且我也不能全戴上 是吧
And I can't wear all of them, or can I?
挑着戴啊
Pick one.
不行 要是只戴一个
No. Because then I would insult
没戴的那些人不就觉得我是在冒犯他们吗
whoever gave me the ones I'm not wearing and...
当一个你这么优秀的舰长真不容易啊
Must be hard being such an amazing captain.
呃
You, uh...
你是在物色自己的新座舰吗
shopping for a new starship?
上将说了 要什么样的星舰由我来定
Admiral April said I've got my pick.
这儿有各式各样的星舰可供选择
There are about a dozen commissions available.
很好啊
Okay.
那你想要什么样的呢
So, what are you looking for?
深空探索型
Deep space exploration.
但这样的话我就见不到你了
But then I never see you.
或者短距离的外交邮轮
Or short-range diplomatic courier.
但这样我还是会见不到你
But then I still never see you.
我到现在都觉得像是在做梦
It still doesn't feel totally real.
我本该死了的
I should be dead, I'm...
我还活着只是侥天之幸
I'm on borrowed time.
说到这个 我都明白的
Well, you're preaching to the choir on that one.
* 这句话字面意思就是「向唱诗班布道」
你这么说我都能想象出来你在唱诗班的样子了
Now I'm just picturing you in a boys' choir.
其实我以前还真是教堂的侍童
Actually, I was an altar boy.
你是个舰长 你会找到你的船的
You're a captain. You'll find your ship.
我只是希望这个过程能慢一点
I just wish it didn't have to be so soon.
你想说什么呢 舰长
What are you asking me, Captain?
实话说 我也不知道
Frankly, I don't know. I...
我只知道
All I know is that
我还没准备好和你分别
I'm not ready to let you go.
这就有点尴尬了
Well, this is awkward.
不好意思
Right, sorry.
刚刚我说的太过分了
It was too far. That...
逗你的呢
Relax.
我在想 等你和我搬到一起住之后
I was just wondering what you're gonna do
你要怎么办
when I move you into my quarters.
你那些护理头发的瓶瓶罐罐要放在哪
Where will all your hair products go?
嘿
Hey.
我把这个带来了
I-I brought this.
我觉得我应该还给你
I thought you might want it back.
这是给你的礼物
It was a gift.
我何必要反悔
Why would I not wish for you to have it?
之前的事 很抱歉
I'm sorry about earlier.
我没想让你和罗杰的第一次见面那么尴尬
I didn't want you to meet Roger like that.
你脸上那副惊讶的表情
The look of surprise on your face
几乎让我觉得这次失误值了
was almost worth the misstep.
这对我来说也不容易
This isn't easy.
我能问你一个直白的问题吗
May I ask you a direct question?
你哪次问的不直白了
Never known you to be any different.
你说你不希望进入一段
You expressed the desire to remain unattached,
正式的关系
free of commitment.
然而我却带了一个男朋友
And then I bring my new boyfriend
回家过节
home for the holidays.
是啊
Yes.
等我自己搞清楚了之后
When I figure that out for myself,
我发誓我会第一个
I swear you will be the first person
向你解释的
that I explain it to.
事实是 我自己也不知道
The truth is, I don't know.
就这么发生了
It just is.
斯波克
Spock.
我们还能做朋友吗
Are we gonna be okay?
我们今晚在舰上的餐厅有鸡尾酒会
We're having cocktails in the Port Galley tonight.
希望你能来
I hope you'll come.
好吧 我就喝一杯 然后我就要回去训练了
Fine, one drink, then I have to go back and finish training.
之前谁还教我龙舌兰酒能当饭吃的来着
Aren't you the one who taught me tequila is its own food group?
来点龙舌兰能让你冷静下来 伙计
你知道她是我们的通讯官对吧
You realize she's our communications officer, right?
她会的语言 有九百种了吧
She speaks, like, 900 languages.
烦人精姐姐语算是其中一种吗
Is "obnoxious big sister" one of 'em?
别劝她了 贝托 跟我一起去玩吧
Let it go, Beto. You can hang with me.
正合我意
That seems like a plan to me.
等一下 不对劲
Wait one damn minute.
你俩什么情况
This, you two...
跟对方说话的语气就像你们
...talking to each other like you're...
看对方的眼神也是 就像
and looking at each other like you're...
不行 这简直一团乱麻 疯了
No. It's chaos, madness.
你不放心把你最好的朋友交给我吗
You don't trust me with your best friend?
你不放心把你的宝贝弟弟交给我吗
You don't trust me with your baby brother?
行了行了 那我自己去训练了
Okay. Okay, I'll stay for a while.
但是你们不许当着我的面调情
But there will be no more flirting.
绝对不许啊
Literally none.
科尔比博士
So, Dr. Korby.
我是山姆 我得说 我非常敬佩
Uh, Sam. I got to say, I'm a big fan
您在高等古代文明研究方面的贡献
of your work on advanced ancient cultures.
报道说您最近的考古发掘是在瓦迪亚九号星
I read that your latest dig was on Vadia Nine.
是啊
Uh-huh.
那您有爬过迦勒山吗
Uh, have you climbed Mount Caleb?
是啊 我们爬过了
Uh, we did, actually. Yeah.
事实上 爬山的过程还挺浪漫的呢
It was, it was pretty romantic, actually.
斯波克先生
Uh, Mr. Spock.
很高兴你能来
Glad you could join us.
我的工作提早完成了
I finished my work early.
科尔比博士正要给我们讲一个浪漫的故事呢
Dr. Korby was just about to tell us a romantic story.
-噢 那还是别提了 -是啊
- Oh, no,don't worry about it.- No.
-要不改天吧 -你们肯定不想听
- Some other time. - You guys don't want to hear...
-只是个超无聊的故事 -是啊
- Bore the life out of you. - Yeah.
我很乐意聆听
I would like to hear it.
最近我正在学习关于浪漫的知识
I have, of late, become a student of romance.
忽然好渴
Sudden thirst.
贝托 跟我一起去拿些饮料来
Beto, give me a hand with some drinks.
好吧 是这样的
Okay. Um... Well,
那是我小时候的事情了
uh, when I was a little girl,
每次我出门之前
whenever I would go away on a trip--
无论是去露营还是去学校
to camp, to school--
我妈妈都会对我说
my mother would always say to me,
「克丽丝 我希望你能找到属于你的阳光」
"Chrissy, I hope you find the sun..."
「愿你寻得属于自己的日月星辰」
"I hope you find the sun and the moon and the stars."
嗯
Yeah.
结果到头来 这句话成了她
And they turned out to be the last words
对我说的最后一句话
she ever said to me.
然后
And, um,
是这样 迦勒山刚好要高过太阳平面
Mount Caleb actually happens to break the solar plane.
所以太阳和月亮会同时出现
So, um, the sun and the moon are visible at the same time.
那天又是我妈妈的生日
And it was my mother's birthday.
我没有把这事告诉过任何人
And I didn't tell anybody
我一向如此
'cause I never do.
可是他注意到我情绪低落
Uh, but he just noticed that I was down and...
注意到这两件事的关联了
remembered the story and put two and two together.
我们到达山顶的时候
And when we got to the top...
登上山顶之后
When we got to the top,
我向她展示了绝美的天空
I showed her the stunning sky
然后送给她这个
and gave her this.
提拉利安星钻
Tilaryan Star Gems.
-这可是举世罕见的珍宝 -没错
- They're incredibly rare. - Yeah.
然后他说
And he said,
「你好像很难过
"You looked sad.
所以我想要送给你日月星辰」
I wanted to give you the sun and the moon and the stars."
-祭酒来啦 -大家都来一杯
- Libations. - Shots, everybody!
-妙啊 -谢天谢地
- Fun. - Thank God.
好酷的手镯 哪里来的
Ooh, that's a cool bracelet. Where'd you get it?
晚上好
Good evening.
* 假装成瓦肯酒保的是特雷兰 见《原初系列》1x08「哥索斯的侍从」
准备好换一换口味了吗
Ready for a change?
我从未知晓 舰上有一位瓦肯酒保
I was not aware we had a Vulcan bartender.
临时调任
Temporary posting.
路过而已
Just passing through.
那么 要来一点不同 但是很赞的东西吗
So, something different but better?
你一定想尝尝的东西
Something you definitely want?
嗯 可以接受
Yes, that would be fine.
太好了
Fantastic.
我正好有你想要的
I have just the thing.
晃一晃酒杯 让香气散发出来
Swirl it around. Brings out the aroma.
别喝得太急
Don't drink it too fast.
会上头哦
It'll go right to your head.
早上好啊
Good morning.
早上好 你也是
Good morning back.
今晚不能和我睡一起哦
Tonight, no sleepover.
婚礼当天见到自己的新娘 会倒霉的
It is bad luck to see your bride on the day of your wedding.
科学官个人日志
Science Officer's personal log.
星历2251.7
Stardate 2251.7.
经过三个月的驻扎
After a three-month billet,
我们与戈恩人交战造成的损伤
the battle scars of our encounter with the Gorn
已经被全数修复
are all but erased.
在一号星际基地的停靠期间
And while docked at Starbase One,
我们的船员在为难得一遇的欢乐时刻做准备
our crew prepares to celebrate a rare and joyous occasion,
那就是我自己和查普尔护士的婚礼
the wedding nuptials between myself and Nurse Chapel.
你的第一支舞绝对会惊艳四座
Your first dance is going to be great.
你进步很大
You're improving.
并非如此
Untrue.
我从未理解 为什么需要用欺骗
I've never understood the need for deception
来缓和潜在的负面反应
to smooth a potential negative reaction.
和你结婚怕是要享受咯
You're just going to excel at marriage.
你结过婚吗
Have you ever been married?
我吗 绝对不可能
Me? God no.
我不是那种适合长期关系的人
I'm not really the commitment type.
我的童年经历 让我很难接受稳定的情感依赖
My childhood didn't really set me up for a stable attachment.
但是呢 一边跑一边朝后开枪
Now, shooting backwards while running,
我倒是很在行
that I can do.
我必须说 你最近看起来轻松了许多
Of late, I must say you have seemed lighter.
史波克 如果你现在还没练好
Spock, if you don't have it by now,
那就太晚了
then it's too late.
谢谢你 拉安
Thank you, La'An.
你一直是我很好的朋友
You have been a good friend to me.
我该去准备彩排了
I must prepare for the rehearsal.
各就各位 我们还有很多要做呢
Places, everyone! We have much to do.
婚礼又不是过家家 说办就能办的
A wedding doesn't just plan itself overnight, you know.
彩排就和正式仪式一模一样
And the rehearsal is just like the real thing,
只是可以穿舒服点的鞋子
only with comfortable shoes.
你们这位婚礼策划可真够可以的
This wedding planner of yours is something.
真没想到安多利人会这么注重细节
Never thought of Andorians as being so detail-oriented.
你们两个 就像太空舱里的两颗豆子
You two, you're like two peas in a space pod.
太登对啦
So delightful.
那就先从蛋糕开始吧
Let's start with the cake.
等等 罗杰去哪里了
Wait, uh, where's Roger?
我觉得我们应该等等伴郎吧
I feel like we should probably wait for my best man.
我来了
I'm here.
来了
I am here.
我还带来了蛋糕
And I have the cakes.
太好了
Excellent.
新鲜出炉 可香了
Oh, yeah. Very nice.
克莉丝汀 我可以和你聊一下
Christine, I couldn't just chat...
稍后吧 科尔比先生
Uh, later, Mr. Korby.
是博士
Doctor.
叫我科尔比博士
Dr. Korby.
好吧
Fine.
其实我还有一个特别的伴郎任务
Actually, I have a special best man task
专门需要你
just for you.
你能在那边等我一会儿吗
Could you wait for me way over there?
越快越好
Quick as you can.
真听话
Good one.
那么 史波克先生
Now, Mr. Spock.
我知道你想举办一场地球人风格的婚礼
I know you wanted to embrace a human-type wedding,
不过 要不要考虑混搭风
but what about fusion style?
我管它叫「人肯式」
I call this "Hu-can."
或者「瓦曼风」
Or "Vul-man."
尝尝看吧
Just try it.
你不喜欢吗
You hate it?
我没想到蛋糕会这么辣 这么咸
I was not expecting cake with quite so much heat and brine.
再尝一次 好不好
Let's try that again, shall we?
我来尝一块
Oh, I'll go.
史波克开玩笑的 蛋糕很美味啊
Spock's joking, this is delicious.
我能尝到巧克力和
Is it chocolate and, um...
瓦肯帕克洛尔?
Vulcan pahklor?
没错 帕克洛尔
Indeed, pahklor.
没什么能比帕克罗更能表达爱意了
Nothing says love like pahklor.
我刚才一定是弄错了
I must've been mistaken before.
确实很好吃
This is quite good.
不是很好 是完美
Not just good but perfect,
就像你们后面的婚礼一样
like your wedding is going to be.
现在来讨论一下编舞吧
Let's talk about choreography.
史波克 假设我们没有婚斗仪式这个环节
Spock, assuming we're not going to have a Kal-if-fee situation,
* 婚斗仪式是瓦肯习俗中两个瓦肯男性为了女性交配对象决斗至死的仪式
你会在那边的结婚圣坛
I have you over on the altar
你的伴郎派克舰长就在前排
and your best man Captain Pike in the front row
就在这里
just here.
乔瑟夫和乌娜呢
Joseph and Una.
你们簇拥着克莉丝汀 跳着华尔兹通过走道
I see you waltzing Christine down the aisle
然后将她转入史波克的臂弯
and then spin her into Spock's arms.
我可没有练习这个
I didn't practice that.
我为你准备了一个惊喜 害羞的新娘
I have a surprise for you, my blushing bride.
从地球的蒙福特州远道而来
Arrived all the way from Vermont, Earth
今早收到的
this morning.
我妈妈的手捧花?
My mother's flowers?
她在婚礼后把手捧花保存起来了
She had these preserved after her wedding.
噢不
Oh, no.
这些花看着是死透了啊
Those flowers look dead.
它们必须储存在精确的2.7度下
These were supposed to be stored at exactly 2.7 degrees.
-说真的 -我很抱歉 克莉丝汀
- I mean, the... - I'm so sorry, Christine.
有任何办法能拯救这些花吗
Is there any way to salvage them?
我的住舱里有一个复水仪
I-I have a rehydrator in my quarters.
听我说一句吧
I'll tell you what.
可能它们只是需要出来透透气
Maybe they just need to breathe.
看吧
I mean...
我的天 怎么可能
Oh, my God. What?
还真可以啊 我简直不敢相信
It worked. I can't believe it.
这就是为什么我们要彩排
This is why we have rehearsal.
既然解决了这个危机
And with that avertation of the latest crisis,
让我们继续吧
let's continue.
等你们两个都站在圣坛
With both at the altar,
交换了戒指 大功告成
we have the rings exchanged, and voilà.
每个人都像特纳兰蝙蝠一样开心
Everyone's as happy as a Ternaran bat.
克莉丝汀 我能和你说两句吗 拜托
Uh, Christine, can we just chat for two seconds, please?
很不巧 彩排刚刚结束
Unfortunately, rehearsal has just finished,
也就是说 查普尔护士 我必须要把你赶走
which means, Nurse Chapel, I'm gonna have to scoop you away
去最后试一次礼服
for your final fitting.
快点 该动身啦
So quickly, here we go.
拜托 别告诉你在婚礼上也准备穿着这件夹克
Please tell me you're not gonna wear that jacket on the day,
科布斯
Korbs.
嗨 你好吗 最近过得怎么样
Hey, how are you? How're you doing?
科尔比博士 你在做什么
Dr. Korby, what are you doing?
我 呃
I'm, um...
想删掉你的婚礼誓词
...trying to delete your vows.
我就知道 蛋糕 还有手捧花
I knew it. The cake, the flowers,
你想要毁掉我们的婚礼
you are trying to sabotage our wedding.
是啊 你不能和克莉丝汀结婚
Yeah, y-you can't marry Christine.
是因为你爱上她了吗
Are you in love with her?
我是喜欢她 但这不是我这么做的原因
Yes. But that's not the reason.
不完全是
Well, not entirely.
听着 这场婚礼就不应该发生 明白吗
Look, this wedding is not supposed to happen, okay?
我不知道怎么向你解释
Uh, I can't fully explain it,
但是我们所在的现实被改变了
but our reality has shifted.
我觉得你该离开了 博士
I think you should leave, Doctor.
听我说完
Just listen.
克莉丝汀和我昨天才来到进取号
Yesterday, Christine and I arrived on the Enterprise
我们是来参加联邦建立百年纪念日的
to attend the Federation's Centennial.
我们特地把婚礼选在这个百年庆典的良辰吉日
We specifically chose the centennial as our wedding day.
不不不 我们就是为了纪念日才来到这里的
No, no, no, no. It is the reason we are here.
到昨天为止 还没有什么婚礼
As of yesterday, there was no wedding.
还没有什么「你和查普尔护士彼此爱恋」这一套
There was no "you and Nurse Chapel."
她明明和我在一起
She and I were together.
你是作为她的好朋友来参加婚礼的
You arrived together because you are best friends.
不 我们不是朋友 我们彼此相爱
No, not as best friends, romantically we are together.
只是似乎只有我一个人还记得这些事
But I seem to be the only one here that remembers that.
三个月前 我向查普尔求婚
I proposed to Christine three months ago,
这一切都发生在她去参加你的研究项目之前
before she embarked on her fellowship with you.
我好不容易才拿到祖母的订婚戒指
I procured my grandmother's engagement ring--
你说的这些都没发生过
None of that happened.
为什么只有我一个人记得
Why am I the only one that remembers this?
你们在她去进修之前就分手了
You parted ways before the fellowship.
确实 我第一次见到她的时候 她看起来很忧郁
And yeah, when I met her, at first, she was pretty gloomy.
我理解 分手确实让人难过
I get it, endings are... are difficult.
博士 我认为你应该去医务室检查下脑子
I think you should visit sickbay, Doc--
等等
Wait.
一开始 她确实只是学生
At first, she was a fellow, yes.
但事情很快就发生了变化
But she quickly became more.
她逐渐赶上
An equal.
不久之后 她在瓦迪亚九星的发掘现场与我共事那会
After a while, she was running the excavation site on Vadia Nine with me.
某天晚上 我们一起待到很晚
And one night, we stayed late.
我给她读了一首聂鲁达的诗
And I read her a poem by Neruda.
「我渴望你的嘴唇 你的嗓音 你的秀发」
"I crave your mouth, your voice, your hair."
* 出自聂努达《一百首爱的十四行诗·第十一首》
然后她
And she, um...
她吻了我
She kissed me--
哦 不好
Oh, no.
不好
请冷静 科尔比博士
Please, Dr. Korby.
我需要向你道歉
I owe you an apology.
抱歉我打了你
Yes, for that.
而且 你说的对
But also, you were right.
现实确实被改变了
Reality has been changed.
一切都与原来不同
None of this is how it should be.
你想起来了?
So you remember?
是的
I do.
但我不确定是什么原因造成的
But I am not entirely sure why.
你有把这件事告诉克莉丝汀吗
Have you tried telling Christine?
我尝试过 但是她没有听进去
Yes, but she shut me down.
如此广泛的幻觉产生的原因
I've considered several possible explanations
可能有以下几个
for this mass delusion.
理论一 我们身处于一个平行宇宙中
First, that this is an alternate dimension.
但我已经检查了自身的相位变化 并无异常
I've already checked myself for phase variance and found none.
理论二 我们遭遇了某种环境致幻剂
Second theory: exposure to an environmental hallucinogen.
克莉丝汀和我同时到达进取号 所以
Christine and I arrived at the same time, so...
若这条理论成立 你也应当受到影响
You would both be unaffected.
说不定是某种外来病毒感染
Alien virus?
生物过滤器近期刚完成了升级 所以应该不是病毒造成的
The bio-filters have been recently upgraded.
或者是某种不确定场
Perhaps an improbability field?
* 出自《奇异新世界》2x09「子空间狂想曲」
我们遇到过这种情况 导致我们一直在
We once entered one that made us...
歌唱
sing.
可能吧
Perhaps.
我已经知晓了现状
Now that I am aware of the situation,
我不会继续参加这场婚礼仪式了
I will obviously not proceed with the nuptials.
你大概没得选
You may not have a choice.
每当我试图阻止这场婚礼
Every time I've tried to stop this wedding,
就会有东西妨碍我
something has interfered.
你是觉得这件事中
You are suggesting the presence
有某种具有改变现实能力的
of an advanced intelligent life-form
高级智慧生命体在干涉
with reality-altering capabilities.
是的
Yes.
但为什么只有你没有受到影响
But why leave you unaffected?
这个嘛
Well...
可能是我缜密的理性思维
...my rigorous intellect may have
使我的头脑免受幻觉的影响
shielded my mind from the illusion.
博士
Doctor.
如果这个条件成立
If one of our intellects could bestow immunity,
我确信不受影响的一定不会是你
I am confident it would not be yours.
跟我来 我们可以去科学实验室对整艘船进行扫描
Come. We can use the science lab to scan the ship.
如果有异常能量出现 应该可以检测到
Any anomalous energy should be detectable.
棒极了 又是那个讨厌的安多利安人
Great. Another Andorian annoyance.
啊 终于找到你了
Ah, there you are!
在这最幸福的婚礼的前夕
Greetings and many felicitations
向你致以真诚的问候
on this happiest of wedding eves.
哦 科尔比先生
Oh, Mr. Korby.
是博士
Doctor.
怎么哪儿都有你
You really are everywhere, aren't you?
狗皮膏药似的
Bit like a rash.
说到这个 婚礼那边的其他宾客
Speaking of which, the rest of the bridal party
正在享受面部护理
are enjoying facials.
你要不要也去体验一下
Perhaps you should join them.
你看起来有点呆
Are you sleeping?
是不是没睡好
黑眼圈这么重 肯定是没睡好
The bags beneath your eyes say no.
我亲爱的新郎 你看这些衣服怎么样
My darling groom, what do you think of this?
这个颜色很衬你的瞳色
The color really brings out your eyes.
可以延后吗 我现在有一些紧急事务需要处理
Could this wait? I have urgent duties to attend to.
别傻了
Don't be silly.
现在 你最重要的任务就是结婚
Right now, your most important mission is matrimony.
这件就可以了
That one will be fine.
我们得走了
Come. We must go.
说了是博士
It's Doctor.
哎呦 博士呢
"It's Doctor."
这实验室挺不错
Nice lab.
执行全舰扫描程序 这应该会耗费几分钟
Initiating ship-wide scan now. It will take a few minutes.
我在想你是怎么意识到这是一场幻觉的
I was thinking about how it was that you became disillusioned.
我挥出那一拳的那一瞬间
At the moment I punched you,
就好像我脑海中迷雾消散了
it was as if a fog in my mind lifted,
然后我就知道了
and I knew.
也许是肾上腺素和皮质醇的突然爆发造成的
Perhaps it was the sudden burst of adrenaline and cortisol that did it.
也有可能是因为
It is also possible that whatever power
当我们直面真相的时候
is creating this false reality cannot be maintained
这场错误的幻觉就无法维持下去了
when so directly confronted with the truth.
无论如何 我们都需要找到办法
Regardless, we must find a way
告知舰长当前的情况
to communicate the situation to the captain.
那祝你好运了
Good luck with that.
终于找到你了
There you are.
你怎么不在自己的房间待着
You were supposed to meet me in your quarters.
不管这是什么 我都不能喝
Whatever this is, I cannot.
山姆 你带来的是什么
Sam! What do we have here?
来选明天婚宴主桌要上的葡萄酒吧
These are the wine selections for the head table tomorrow.
请你认真听我说 柯克上尉
Listen to me very carefully, Lieutenant Kirk.
进取号停泊在一号星站是为了
Enterprise came to Starbase One
庆祝联邦建立百年纪念日
to celebrate the Federation Centennial.
而不是婚礼
Not a wedding.
查普尔护士早已和我分手
Nurse Chapel and I are no longer a couple.
我们不会结婚
We are not getting married.
你正处于一种未知现象的影响下
You are suffering from an unknown phenomenon.
很有可能我们遭到了某种袭击
It is possible we are all under attack.
我懂的
I get it.
我理解你 史波克 你想打退堂鼓
I get it, Spock, you have cold feet.
这太正常了 你听我说
It's totally normal, look--
给我一拳
Punch me.
啥
What?
我揍你干什么
I'm not gonna punch you.
你做事马虎
You are sloppy.
不如你的兄弟聪明
Less intelligent than your brother.
没有人喜欢你的胡子
No one likes your mustache.
而且你对酒的品味很差
And you have terrible taste in wine.
如果我在你婚礼前夕给你打得眼眶乌青
If I gave you a black eye the day before your wedding,
克莉丝汀会杀了我的
Christine would kill me.
扫描完成
Scan complete.
当前并未检测到异常能量读数
There are no anomalous energy readings present.
就要霞多丽葡萄酒吧
Perhaps the chardonnay.
舰长 我们需要报告紧急情况
Sir, we have an urgent situation.
我非常清楚 少校
I am aware, Lieutenant.
喝了这个就好了
And there. Fixed that.
史波克先生 欢迎来到你的单身派对
Mr. Spock, welcome to your bachelor party.
-嘿 -史波克哟
- Hey. - Spock-o!
我准备了所有你喜欢的东西
Spock! I prepared all of your favorites.
瓦肯巨贝 普克塔
Jumbo mollusk, Pok-tar, and
* 分别出自《深空九号》2x06 以及《进取号》1x08
还有看看我找到了什么
look what I found.
鲁土格
Lutrog.
还有为我们其他人准备的
And something imbibable for the rest of us:
蜥蜴白兰地
Saurian brandy.
哦 说实话 我不怎么喝酒
Oh, honestly, I'm not really much of a drinker.
我几乎碰不了那东西
I hardly touch the stuff.
我觉得吧 按照习俗
I believe tradition dictates
准新郎在踏入婚姻坟墓之前 得先说段祝酒词
the groom-to-be give us a toast before he walks the plank.
对啊 演讲
Yes, speech.
来吧 史波克先生
Come on, Mr. Spock.
我们所在的现实遭到了改变
Our reality has been changed.
查普尔护士早已和我分手
Nurse Chapel and I are not together.
她现在和科尔比博士恋爱了
She is in love with Dr. Korby,
但现在只有我和他记得这件事
and only he and I remember this.
敬史波克 世界上最幸运的人
To Spock, the luckiest man in the world.
对 敬史波克
Yes, to Spock.
-史波克先生 -干杯
- Mr. Spock. - Cheers.
舰长 进取号正在遭受大规模幻觉影响
Captain, Enterprise is experiencing a mass delusion.
我就说吧 他又打退堂鼓了
I told you. Cold feet.
我没有在打鼓 多谢关心
My feet are perfectly warm, thank you.
我是认真的
This is serious.
放轻松 史波克
Relax, Mr. Spock.
我知道这对你来说很难
Which I know is difficult for you.
所以才要请你吃鲁土格
That's why the Lutrog.
要慢点吃啊
Careful with that.
到目前为止 情况似乎已经很清楚
It seems clear by now that being confronted
仅仅告知大家真相并不足以打破这种魔咒
with the truth is not enough to break the spell.
这就只剩下情感反应这一途径了
Which leaves us with emotional response.
但我们已经观察到了各种各样的情感
But we have seen a range of emotions
却没有一种能驱散这种幻觉
and yet none dispel the delusion.
生气 愤怒 这是最强烈的一种情感了
Anger, rage, it's one of the most powerful emotions there is.
或许需要另一种同样强烈的情感
Perhaps another equally powerful emotion.
比如什么
Like what?
爱
Love.
对了史波克 我差点忘了
Mr. Spock, I almost forgot,
婚礼策划人请你评价一下座位安排表如何
the wedding planner asked you to weigh in on the seating arrangement.
不介意的话 请看看第八排
Take a look at row eight, if you don't mind.
呃 舰长
Uh, Captain?
一共有多少人受邀出席了这场婚礼
How many guests are invited to the wedding?
全体船员以及 107名登记的来宾
All the crew and, uh, 107 registered guests.
谢了
Thanks.
计算机 当前进取号上
Computer, how many individuals
除了船员和登记的来宾
are currently aboard the Enterprise
还有多少其他个体的存在
besides crew and registered guests?
一个
One.
婚礼有个不速之客
We have a wedding crasher.
就藏在我们眼皮底下
Hiding in plain sight.
计算机 定位该个体的位置
Computer, locate that individual.
符合条件的个体位于左舷餐厅
The individual fitting that description is in the Port Galley.
史波克 你要去哪
Spock, where you going?
待会还要去唱卡拉OK呢
We're gonna do karaoke.
噢 科尔比先生 史波克先生
Oh, Mr. Korby, Mr. Spock.
你们不是应该在参加单身派对吗
Shouldn't you be at your bachelor party?
我正在准备招待会的特调饮品
I'm working on a specialty drink for the reception.
二位觉得石榴汁怎么样
How do we feel about pomegranate?
我不需要一场狂欢宴
I do not need a bacchanal.
那你就该好好睡个美容觉
Then you should get your beauty rest.
我现在也睡不着
I do not need to sleep.
那就数玛梵入睡吧
Count tribbles, then.
你 你就是那个实体
You. You are the entity.
哦 史波克先生
Oh, Mr. Spock.
你那瓦肯式幽默感每次都能逗到我
Your Vulcan sense of humor gets me every time.
还记得吗 我是你的婚礼策划人呀
I'm your wedding planner, remember?
你旋转着走进我的办公室 满心沉醉在爱意中
You twirled into my office, drunk on love,
梦想着一场既梦幻又让人喜不自胜的婚礼
wishing for a wedding day full of magic and unspeakable joy.
梦想?
A wish?
那一晚 就在这个地方
That night, here in the Port Galley,
你那会也是酒保
you were the bartender then, too.
我希望我和克莉丝汀之间的情况能有所不同
I wished things could be different with Christine.
而你让它成为了现实
And you made it so.
不用谢
You're welcome.
这不重要
It does not matter.
我们不会进行这场婚礼
We are not going through with the wedding.
你必须将其复原
You have to fix this.
你不能就这样操控人们的思想
You can't just control people's minds.
我爱怎么样就怎么样
I can do anything I want.
我是个婚礼策划师
I am a wedding planner.
此外 我不喜欢被别人破坏我的计划
And I do not like it when people ruin my plans.
醒一醒 史波克先生
Wakey wakey, Mr. Spock.
今天是你的大喜之日
It's your big day.
你不能强迫我继续演这场戏
You cannot force me to continue this charade.
哎呦 真的假的
Can't I, though?
要是你惹我生气的话
Do you know what would happen
不用想大家会是什么样的下场吧
to everyone if you made me mad?
我甚至都想象不出来下场
I don't think I can even imagine it.
哇 快看
Well, look at that.
我的小型瓦肯生态皿
My own little Vulcan terrarium.
我的朋友们肯定羡慕坏了
My friends will be so jealous.
现在知道要乖乖听话了吗
I do hope you'll play along now, yes?
我听到婚礼的钟声敲响了
I can hear the wedding bells.
哎哟 看看你 真是帅气啊
Ah! Look at you, you look great.
所以婚礼都应该在沙滩上进行
All weddings should be on the beach
而且所有人都应该穿着短裤
and everyone should be in shorts.
好吧
Okay.
我一直在找你
I have been searching for you.
他逼着我做伴郎
He's made me the maid of honor.
他说如果我不乖乖照做的话
And he says if I don't play along,
他要把我们都发配到玉米地里去
he's gonna wish us all to a cornfield.
* 发配到玉米地是《阴阳魔界》里的梗 见该剧集的3x08
我不明白玉米地有什么特殊的含义
I do not understand the significance of this wish.
这是个梗 算了
It's from a... Doesn't matter.
他的意思是把我们都从现实中抹除
He's talking about wiping us from all of existence.
是的 他也这样威胁我了
Yes, he made this threat to me as well.
你得把这件事做完
You're gonna have to go through with this.
就是 可能唯一的解决办法
Just... Maybe that's the only way to end it,
就是顺着他来
play his game.
史波克 到时候了
It's time, Spock.
咱们让你成婚吧
Let's get you married.
请大家落座
Please be seated.
今日能齐聚一堂
What a delight
共同见证如此特别的时刻
to be gathered here today to celebrate
真是令人欣喜
something so special,
一种比最快的星舰更强大的力量
a force more powerful than the fastest starship.
人类称之为爱
Humans call it love,
而我听说 爱可以战胜一切
and I'm told love can conquer all things.
克莉丝汀
Christine--
嘘 早了
Shh. Not yet.
你们都有准备誓词吧
Do you both have your vows?
不行
No.
不
No!
我反对
I object.
还没到那个环节呢
We're not there yet.
罗杰 你在干什么
Roger, what are you doing?
克莉丝汀 你必须停下
Christine, you have to stop this.
该停下的是你
You stop.
你不能就这样改变别人的感受
You can't just make people feel things
改变别人的真情实感
that they don't really feel!
够了
That's it.
请继续 史波克先生
Please, continue, Mr. Spock.
人类诗人聂鲁达曾写道
The human poet Neruda wrote,
「我渴望你的嘴唇 你的嗓音
"I crave your mouth, your voice,
你的秀发
"your hair.
我不说话 不吃喝
"Silent and starving,
游荡在街头巷尾
"I prowl through the streets.
面包无法果腹
"Bread does not nourish me,
黎明只会令我发狂
"dawn disrupts me,
整日里
"all day
我追寻你脚步流水般的韵姿」
I hunt for the liquid measure of your steps."
这就是爱你的感觉 克莉丝汀
This is what it is like to love you, Christine.
而值得你的爱的人
And the person worthy of your love,
必须要勇敢
they must be courageous.
不能沉溺迷失
They cannot be drowning.
不能摇摆不定
They cannot be unsure
也不能任由自己的情感风暴裹挟
or at the mercy of their own emotional storms.
他必须是你灵魂的港湾
They must be a safe harbor.
要能为你守住一方宁静
They must have the ability to hold space for you.
去看到你
To see you.
最真实的你
Just you.
他必须听得见你未曾出口的呼唤
They must be able to hear your unuttered call.
要能够把一切都交予你
They must be able to give you everything.
必须能把
They must offer you the moon
日月星辰
and the sun and the stars
都一并赠予你
all at once.
我并不清楚你母亲的生日是哪天
I did not know when it was your mother's birthday.
我没告诉你
I didn't tell you.
这不是谁的错
It's no one's fault.
这不对 史波克
This is wrong, Spock.
我们不应该结婚
We're not supposed to be getting married.
对
No.
我们不应该
We are not.
你俩应该呀
Yes, you are.
罗杰
Roger...
Roger.
呃 不 他是只狗
Well, no, he's a dog,
所以 不行
so... No!
我绝对不允许
No, no, no, no, no!
够了
That is it.
大家都得死
Everybody dies.
就从这条狗开始
And I'm starting with the dog.
你离他远点
You keep away from him.
准备好迎接你们的末日吧
Prepare for a cavalcade of death.
你们今晚谁也别想吃到婚礼蛋糕
No one gets a wedding cake slice tonight.
你死定了
You're going to die.
你要死翘翘了
You'll be dead.
然后你 戴着皇冠的 脑子里装的啥
And you with the crown, what were you thinking?
是想抢新娘风头吗
Tried to outshine the bride?
还有你们几个蓝脸的 你们明知道我穿着蓝色衣服
And you blue faces, you could see I was in blue.
你们哪来的胆
How dare you.
去死吧你
Death to you.
还有后面那个
And you at the back
连张嘴都没有
with no mouth.
就是你
Yes, you.
但说实话 我挺喜欢的
Actually, that's... I like that.
就放过你吧
You can, you can live.
这是什么情况
What is this?
* 配音演员同时也是Q的演员 主创也确认这里就是Q
不是现在 老爹
Not now, Dad.
唉 你惹的麻烦也够多了吧
Oh, you've made enough of a mess.
拜托别在这丢人现眼的了
Please, let's not make a scene.
噢 天哪
Oh, my...
克莉丝汀
Christine.
但他们一点都不配合诶
But they're not playing along.
他们压根不听我的
They're not listening to me.
然而你也不听我的话
And you are not listening to me.
还用我再向你说明一遍不听话的下场吗
Shall I show you once more what the consequence is for disobedience?
不用
No.
我会听话的 我保证
I'll be good, I promise.
等等 你还只是个孩子吗
Wait, you're a child?
很小的孩子
A very young one.
按照地球时间算才八千岁
Only 8,000 of your Earth years.
是八千零二十岁 爹
8,020, Dad.
该走了
It's time to go.
我还不想走
I don't want to go.
等一下 在你离开之前
Wait, before you leave...
我想知道你为什么这么做
...might I ask why?
这个嘛
Well...
看那家伙
Look at him.
我发现他在老家那边挖来挖去的
I spotted him digging in the dirt on the old homeworld.
他实在是完美 一个又帅又聪明的人
He's just so handsome and smart and perfect.
看到他就火大
It's just annoying.
是 这确实合乎逻辑
Yes, that does make perfect sense.
喂
Oy.
现在 让其他人恢复正常
Now, free the rest of them.
好吧
Okay.
拜拜咯
Tallyho.
玩你们玩的很开心
You've all been lots of fun.
好了大家 没事了 没事了
Okay, everybody, all right, all right,
大家听我说下
all right, okay, all right.
那个 呃 刚刚那件事很奇怪
That was, uh, that-that-that... that was strange.
这场什么婚礼的共同幻觉
A shared delusion about a wedding
可真是个新鲜事 是吧
is a new one, isn't it?
好吧 呃 联邦日
Okay... Uh, Federation Day.
在2161年 星联的创始种族们
2161, the, uh, founding species
聚集在一起创立了 呃 星际联邦
came together to create, uh, the Federation.
呃 主要是为了回应
Um, largely in response
我们与其他外星种族的「友好互动」
to our interactions with other foreign species.
这期间发生了一些非常尴尬的事情
Some of them very awkward.
呃 所以用一种
Uh, so it's only fitting
与其同样尴尬的活动
that-that our-our centennial be marked
来纪念联邦成立百年
by a-a-a similar awkward,
挺合适的
uh, interaction.
总之 今天酒吧畅饮
And the bar is open.
这看着好好喝
Those look incredible.
* 这里的酒保是埃多斯人 这也是该种族首次在真人剧集中出现 之前均是在动画剧集中出现
可以给你调一杯 但这是阿拉妮黑麦威士忌
I'll make you one, but it's Alanni Rye.
它会在你的食道和它下面的东西
It will burn a hole through your esophagus
全部蚀穿个洞出来
and whatever is below your esophagus.
地板可能也难逃一劫
And maybe the floor.
那就请给我两品脱吉尼斯黑啤吧
Two pints of Guinness, please.
这个也许稳妥点
Probably a safer bet.
你是进取号上的医官吗
Are you the doctor from the Enterprise?
约瑟夫·姆'本加
Joseph M'Benga.
我有点想念你戴着花冠的样子了
You know, I kind of miss the flower crown.
-是吗 -是啊
- Oh, yeah? - Mm.
我也有点想念
I kind of miss the big green veil thing
你穿的那件绿色婚纱了
you had going on.
可以说 不是每个女孩都梦想着
Well, I can tell you it is not every girl's dream
被一个宇宙骗子利用情感玩过家家
to have a cosmic trickster play dress-up dolls
摆布她的情绪
with her emotions
还让她嫁错了人
and make her marry the wrong man.
这过去的四十八个小时
The last 48 hours have been...
罗杰
Roger.
我明白
I know.
我也一样
Me, too.
好了 我们就去跳舞吧
Now, let's go dance
以后谁再也别提这事了
and never talk about this ever.
成交
Deal.
你和我想的一样吗
You thinking what I'm thinking?
但我们得处理得好才行
If we play our cards right.
噢 我们只是想和你说
Oh, we were just saying that an artist
这么才华横溢的艺术家
with such prodigious skills
待在星站上真是大材小用了
shouldn't be confined to a starbase.
如果你的意思是想给我一个星舰上的岗位
If you're offering me a job on a starship,
我乐意效劳
my answer is yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 幸会幸会 - 谢谢
- Pleasure meeting you. - Thank you.
我刚刚与星际舰队公关部的负责人
I just had a very interesting conversation
进行了一次有趣的对谈
with the Chancellor of Starfleet's Public Relations.
是吗
Yeah?
他们有意向让我拍一部星际舰队的纪录片电影
They may commission a feature-length documentary of Starfleet.
那个负责人挺喜欢我
Well, the Chancellor likes me,
我可以跟他多美言几句
so I'll put in a good word.
你知道的 只要能烦到艾丽卡
You know, anything to annoy Erica.
我们要去烦艾丽卡吗
Shall we annoy Erica?
敬烦人的艾丽卡
To annoying Erica.
你刚刚的演讲可真精彩
That was a beautiful speech.
是的 大概吧
Yes. I suppose so.
爱有万千形态 史波克先生
Love comes in all forms, Mr. Spock,
而你给了她属于你的那份
and you gave her yours.
我并不后悔
And I have no regrets.
但努力到头来 还是付诸东流了
Still, it is a waste.
什么努力
What is?
你最近的时间都花在学习跳舞上了
Well, you spent all this time learning to dance,
结果你现在光坐着
and now you're just
啥都不用
sitting on it.
毕竟 你的肩膀位置都已经
After all, your shoulder placement
精确测量好了 不是吗
has been measured precisely, has it not?
如果我没记错的话
If I'm not mistaken,
你说不需要精确测量
I am not supposed to measure them.
我该让它们顺其自然
I am supposed to let them flow.
上尉
Lieutenant...
你是在邀请我共舞吗
are you asking me to dance?
吉特巴舞
♪ Jitterbug ♪
你来上
It's all you.
吉特巴舞
♪ Jitterbug ♪
你让我的小心脏砰砰直跳
♪ You put the boom boom into my heart ♪
当你的爱降临时 你让我的灵魂飞上云霄
♪ You send my soul sky high when your loving starts ♪
我满脑子跳着吉特巴舞
♪ Jitterbug into my brain ♪
邦邦邦 我成了抖腿狂魔
♪ Goes a bang-bang-bang till my feet do the same ♪
但是有东西左右着你的心
♪ But something's bugging me, something ain't right ♪
我最好的朋友告诉我你昨晚都干了啥
♪ My best friend told me what you did last night ♪
你把我撇下 让我独自入梦
♪ Left me sleeping in my bed ♪
我还幻想着
♪ I was dreaming ♪
本应和你如影随形
♪ But I should've been with you instead ♪
走之前记得叫醒我
♪ Wake me up before you go-go ♪
突然消失会让我的心神不宁
♪ Don't leave me hanging on like a yo-yo ♪
走之前记得叫醒我
♪ Wake me up before you go-go ♪
因为我不想错过你高涨的一瞬
♪ I don't want to miss it when you hit that high ♪
走之前一定记得叫醒我
♪ Wake me up before you go-go ♪
因为我不想形单影只
♪ 'Cause I'm not planning on going solo ♪
走之前记得叫醒我
♪ Wake me up before you go-go ♪
今晚带我去狂舞吧
♪ Take me dancing tonight ♪
我想好好疯一把
♪ I want to hit that high. ♪